BRYAN MELANSON

bryanm@mun.ca

http://bnuh.github.io

709 749-1273

PROFILE

Innovative software engineer offering years of experience in the full software development lifecycle – from concept through delivery of next-generation applications and customizable solutions. Strong background in project leadership and innovative problem solving partnered with a unique skill set in the creative arts, currently engaged in Memorial University of Newfoundland's Computer Engineering curriculum. Experience programming autonomous sailboats as part of the MUN SailBot team and mentoring sound crews on firsttime filmmaker projects. Accomplished business owner and sound designer with years of experience producing and designing multimedia for clients such as Disney, Fremantle, Collegehumor, ABC and NHL. Self produced albums and video art projects featured in national art galleries, as well as lectures on digital production techniques, interactive sound design and digital copyright

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Support Engineer Nokia Inc. Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

Software Developer Nalcor Energy Dec 2015 - May 2016

Production Coordinator Ludia Inc. Apr 2010 - Aug 2011

EXPERTISE

Scripting
Data Analysis
Agile Methodologies
Software Design
Geographic Image Systems
Web Development
Machine Vision

SKILLS

Linux/Unix Matlab, R, SQL Java, Javascript Python, C++, Bash Django, REST VMWare, OpenStack

- Debugged complex product installations on CentOS/Solaris/RHEL systems, resolving complicated network problems using Open Stack, and VMWare
- Scripting at a Unix/Linux level in bash and Python
- Developed interactive heat map application for analyzing prices and visualizing New York energy market using MATLAB, and SQL
- Scripted the mapping of all major external energy markets using R
- Managed in-house and outsourced content production branch of video, sound, image and transcription teams for "The Price Is Right - Facebook"
- "TPIR Facebook" received 1,000,000 unique users its 1st week

EDUCATION

2015 - 2020 Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering Major

Memorial University of Newfoundland

2015 - 2016 Certificate in Data Science

John Hopkins University, Baltimore MD

Online Course

REFERENCES

Marc Charlebois Supervisor, Nokia Inc. mcharleb@nokia.com

Jeffrey Dawson Co-President, MUN Sailbot jpd546@mun.ca

AFFILIATIONS

IEEE Member 2015 - Present

MUN Sailbot Lead Programmer 2015-2017